For a long time, I thought my problem with faith was simply not believing
good enough. Now I understand it was the conditions that I allowed myself
to live in. Welcome to Life is Your Word, in this show
we understand reality by seeking God first. We're
currently going through a mini -series on the fruit of the Spirit, and today's fruit
patience. Today's reading will be from Luke 8. Jesus said
a parable. A sower went out to sow the seed. Some fell on
the path
and was trampled on.
Some fell on rock and it grew up and
withered for lack of whisper.
Some among thorns and the thorns choked it
and yet some fell on good soil.
And when it grew, it produced a hundredfold.
The parable means this.
The seed is God's word.
Those on the path have heard.
Those on the path have heard the word but the devil takes it
away.
But the devil takes it away from their hearts so they don't believe.
The ones in the rocks hear the word,
receive it with joy,
but have no root.
They've in testing, they fall away.
Those in the thorns are choked
by the cares and riches of life and their
fruit does not mature.
But for the good soil,
these are the ones when they hear the word,
hold it fast in an honest
and good heart and bear fruit with
endurance. I grew up in the church and I heard all about God's
word, and I knew it well. I read the Bible multiple times in high school,
but my life was crowded, trying to pursue
things that I thought were good, but in reality were selfish
desires. I felt pressure, I felt fear,
I was trying to survive instead of being formed by God. So
the word kept getting choked out,
so my fruit couldn't mature,
so the word couldn't take root and my fruit couldn't mature. But
Jesus never blames the seed. There doesn't mean there's anything wrong with the
seed itself. The word is still good.
He points to the soil and soil can change.
Patience only came not because I was trying not because
I learned how to wait better but because I started
tending to my own life making
space letting God work
deeper than my urgency allowing
growth to take time instead of forcing results.
Patience was not the goal. Patience was the fruit.
It showed up when the word
was finally allowed to stay long enough to grow
and produce good fruit.
The seed was always alive what changed was my
life the soil that it grew in.
Patience has never been about waiting but about becoming a place
where life can fully form. How has God taught you about
patience? Share your revelations in the comments. In love and unity, Acebele.